（此为片前广告，正片在3:02开始）
Det-sen Monasnary, Tibet
德赞寺 西藏
15年前
（这里指1980年，因本片故事设定为1995年）
（西藏德赞寺是博士及其同伴杰米、维多利亚首次遭遇大智慧和雪怪的地方，见《神秘博士》老版本第五季第二集《可恶的雪人》 The Abominable Snowmen）
DISTORTED VOICE: Victoria...
维多利亚...
LAMA: What do you seek?
你在找什么？
It's me.
是我
Victoria Waterfield.
维多利亚•沃特菲尔德
Victoria...
维多利亚...
The Great Wheel turns.
命运之轮转动
You have been here once before.
你以前曾经到过这里
A long, long time ago.
很久很久以前
The monastery was in great danger.
那时候寺庙陷入了巨大的危机
You travelled a long, dark journey.
你走过了一段漫长而黑暗的旅程
How can one still so young
怎么可能如此年轻的一个人
know the depths of our darkness?
却知道我们黑暗的深处呢？
What has happened here?
这里发生了什么？
Turn back now.
现在回去吧
- Victoria...
-(GASPS)
My father died far away
我父亲死在一个很远的地方
- on another world.
- There are many other worlds,
- 在另外一个世界  - 有很多其它的世界
other planes.
其它的平面
But I can hear his voice in my thoughts.
但我能在意识里听到他的声音
He's called me all this way.
他一直都在呼唤着我
Demons and hungry ghosts
steal many shapes.
恶魔和饥饿的鬼魂偷了许多形体
Turn away, Victoria.
掉头吧，Victoria
Why do you delay? Release me!
你为什么拖延？释放我吧！
I know he's here. Please tell me where to find him.
我知道他在这里。请告诉我哪里可以找到他
A second time I ask, what do you seek?
我问第二遍，你在找什么？
(EXCLAIMS) What have you done to him?
你把他怎么了？
I'm alone in the darkness.
我独自在黑暗中
Do not disturb it. It is not your father.
别惊扰它，它不是你父亲
- Victoria?  - Let me through!
- 维多利亚？  - 让我过去！
LAMA: I cannot!
我不能
What are you hiding here? Who is it then?
你在这里藏了什么？这又是谁？
A third time I ask,
我问第三遍
what do you seek?
你在找什么？
I want the truth!
我在找真相！
You were expected.
一直在等你
My task is ended. I cannot prevent
your journey into the dark.
我的任务结束了，我不再阻止你踏入黑暗
The truth may light your way.
真相可能可以照亮你的路
Take it.
拿着
I've been alone,
我一直一个人
like you, Victoria.
跟你一样，维多利亚
But together..
但是一起...
Is it you?
是你吗？
1 don't know.
我不知道
They said you were dead.
他们说你已经死了
But in the dreams...
但是在梦里...
- Victoria...  - Father?
- 维多利亚...  - 父亲吗？
(MOANING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
You!
是你！
Find me the Locus!
给我找到人偶！
（Victoria 诞生于19世纪，她父亲因制造时间机器而引来Daleks，然后她和她父亲还有博士一行被 Daleks 带到 Daleks 的母星 Skaro。当 Dalek 朝博士开枪时，她父亲替他挡了一枪，因此牺牲。相关故事参见老版第四季第九集 《Dalek的邪恶》。她父亲其实跟大智慧没有什么交集，只是她自己一直因父亲的死而不能释怀。）
Downtime
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING THROUGH HEADPHONES)
No, Gordy, I told you to play down there while I'm talking.
不，高迪，我跟你说过，我在讲电话的时候你要在下面玩
Now, off you go.
现在，下来吧
Hello? Hello, Beth?
你好？你好，贝丝
Look, they're still there.
看，他们还在那儿
Those two, you know, New World weirdos, Chillys or whatever they're called.
这两个是什么新世界的怪人，他们称呼为鸡仔什么的
Yes, of course, I've called the police
and the council.
是的，当然，我已经报告给警察和理事会了fixme
They all think I'm crazy.
但他们觉得是我不可理喻
The Chillys just vanish when anyone comes, but they're soon back.
一有人来这些鸡仔就消失了，但很快又回来了
I mean, why pick me?
我是说，为什么挑上我？
1 don't know what to do, Beth.
I have no one else to talk to.
我不知道该怎么办，贝丝。我找不到其它人聊这个事
BETH: Look, I'll tell you what. Why
don't you try asking your dad for help?
听着，我告诉你怎么办，你为什么不找你爸爸求助？
What? Sorry, this line's terrible.
什么？抱歉，线路太不好了
My dad? God, no, I couldn't do that.
我爸爸？天呐，不，我不能那么干
It's been at least six years since I spoke to him.
都至少有六年我没有跟他说过话了
Oh, and the computer keeps crashing, so I can't work.
噢，电脑一直宕机，我没法工作
And that damn noise all the time,
it's like being under siege.
一直都有那个该死的噪音，感觉像是被攻击了
Oh, it's disturbing, Gordy.
He can't stay here.
噢，这很烦人，Gordy，他不能待在这里
Would you? Would you really, Beth?
你会吗？你真的会吗，贝丝？
Yes. All right.
是，好吧
But soon. He can't stay here.
但快点，他不能待在这里
Yes, thanks, Beth. Okay, bye.
是，谢谢，贝丝。好，再见
（此角色 Kate Lethbridge-Stewart 是UNIT负责人准将 Gordon Lethbridge-Stewart 的女儿。后来她也成了UNIT的负责人，在《博士之日》中再次亮相，不过不再是这个演员）
Gordy?
高迪？
{(GORDY IMITATING GUN FIRING)
No, Gordy. Not guns. Come on, darling.
不，高迪，别玩枪战了。快来，亲爱的
Now, come on up. Put that down.
Come on to the boat.
现在，上这里来。把那个放下，快到船里来
I've told you before about this.
Now quickly, now.
我以前跟你说过这个。快过来，马上
Here we go. Up you go. Great.
来吧，起来啰，很好
Now, you go and play inside
till Beth comes, all right?
现在，你到里面去玩，知道贝丝过来，好吗？
Off you go.
走你
KATE: Bloody Chillys!
要命的鸡仔！
Leave us alone!
走开！
Leave us alone.
走开
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(LOW GROWLING)
（Piccadilly Circus 皮卡迪利广场是伦敦一个路口的名称，《神秘博士》里有很多故事发生在这个地方）
MAN: (ON RADIO) The sound of the
future on 98.4 New World FM.
未来之声尽在FM98.4新世界电台
ANTHONY: (ON RADIO) And it's a Mega Morning
to all you slickers out there.
对你们所有的懒汉来说, 这是一个超级的早晨
You're jacked into N Treble U,
the ones who share,
你也许是刚刚切换到 NTU ，一个热爱分享的电台
bringing you our daily show
on National FM radio.
为你带来国家调频电台上的每日秀
I'm Anthony, and this is where
the jazzy bright day starts,
我是安东尼，轻松明亮的一天就从这里开始
a New World coming soon,
the way it always will be.
一个新世界迈步走来, 一如既往
0135-666-416.
We want to share that with you all.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
我们期望与你们所有人分享
Meantime, it can be a mean time out there, so let's...
与此同时，它又fixme
(New World University)
（新世界大学）
(COMPUTER READING)
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING
THROUGH HEADPHONES)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Hi, welcome to New World.
How can I help you?
嗨，欢迎来到新世界，有什么可以帮你的？
Sarah-Jane Smith, Metropolitan
magazine.
莎拉•简•史密斯，大都市杂志社
I have an appointment to see your vice chancellor.
我约好去见你的副校长
- I am expected.
- At 11 o'clock. Would you like to take a seat?
- 他在等我  - 是11点，你可以过去坐一会儿吗？
Have the best one yet.
还有一个最佳的座位
- Miss Smith.  - Yes.
- 史密斯小姐  - 我是
Welcome to New World.
欢迎来到新世界
I'm so sorry if we've kept you waiting.
很抱歉让你久等了
Christopher Rice, Marketing Facilitator.
克里斯托弗·赖斯, 营销主持人。
Good morning.
早上好
- You brought the profiles with you, I hope.
- Yes.
- 你把档案带过来了吧，我期望  - 是的
Good. Then let's go on up.
好，那我们上去再说吧
Miss Waterfield, the university's vice chancellor
沃特菲尔德小姐，这所大学的副校长
would like to thank you personally.
她想亲自感谢你
I think the sum agreed was 12k,
assuming all the profiles are complete.
我想总数是一万二，如果所有的档案都完整的话
Er, not quite.
呃，不太完整
Er, Miss Smith, when we were advised of your reputation,
哦，史密斯小姐，当有人向我们推荐你的时候
both Miss Waterfield and I were impressed.
沃特菲尔德小姐和我都很折服
We thought, "What's a few red-tape
barriers to a journalist of this calibre?"
我们想：“对于这样一个路子宽广的记者来说, 那些繁文缛节的障碍算什么？”
But you didn't tell me some of this data
was government classified.
但你们没告诉我这里某些数据是政府机密
(COMPUTER READING) Authorisation failure.
授权失败
You have 10 seconds to enter Stage Three security key.
你有10秒钟时间来输入第三阶段安全密钥
Waterfield.
沃特菲尔德
(COMPUTER READING)
You are attached to Priority Zone Z.
你已经连接到优先区域Z区
（他眼镜中呈现的图像很像是大智慧的三角锥/金字塔）
Yes!
成了！
Look, I still don't know
what New World wants these people for.
看，我还是不知道新世界要这些人的资料做什么
Afraid of unearthing a scandal?
害怕发现一桩丑闻？
Half of them vanish off any records.
他们中有一半从所有记录里消失了
And what is this "London Event”
that connects them?
与他们都相关的这个“伦敦事件”又是什么？
What do you know?
你知道些什么？
I've found records implying
that 25 years ago
我发现有记录显示，在25年前
Central London was evacuated
in an industrial accident.
伦敦市中心因一起工业事故，出现过大规模疏散的事
（应该是指1970年前后的大智慧和雪怪入侵事件，见第五季第二季《恐惧之网》，不过该事件的具体时间不详）
They say it lasted three months.
There are no extant reports.
他们说这事持续了三个月，但目前没有见到有报告保存下来
No one even remembers.
Well, how can that happen?
也没有人记得。你说，这怎么可能呢？
The London Event was a wasted opportunity.
伦敦事件是一次被浪费掉的契机
The world missed out on an interface
with a higher plane of existence.
这个世界错过了一个与更高层面存在打交道的接口
It's no big deal.
这没什么要紧
There will be other chances.
还会有其它机会的
It was totally misunderstood.
这被完全误解了
We all stumbled about
in the unknowing darkness.
我们都还困在莫名的黑暗中
New World seeks to
light the first candle.
新世界致力于点亮第一根蜡烛
Oh, come on.
噢，得了
New World's more than just
a New Age Sunday School.
新世界不仅仅是一所新时代的主日学校
You've got fingers in more pies
than Robert Maxwell.
你们的手指比罗伯特·马克斯维尔还多fixme
I'm afraid we've wasted your time, Miss Smith.
恐怕我们耽误你的时间了，史密斯小姐
You already knew.
你已经知道了
New World has the solution.
新世界找到解决方案了
That's our motto.
这是我们的座右铭
Our programme.
我们的课程
If you've got such high-flying sources,
why employ me?
如果里面有如此高的消息来源，为什么还雇我？
There is one name
missing from your list.
你的清单里少了一个名字
Not to my knowledge.
据我所知没有
But much to ours.
但对我们很重要
Lethbridge-Stewart.
利斯布里奇-斯图尔特。
What do they want old Stewpot for?
他们找这个老斯图做什么？
United Nations Intelligence Task-force
is a paramilitary espionage squad.
UNIT（联合国情报部门行动组）是一个准军事间谍小组
It's the old MI5 story.
这是老旧的军情五处类的故事
Everyone knows it's there, but no
one knows what its real agenda is.
每个人都知道它的存在，但没有人清楚它的真正目标是什么
Even those who work for it.
即使是那些为他工作的人
Alistair Gordon Lethbridge-Stewart figures
largely in its setting up in the '70s.
在它70年代的成立过程中，
Listair Gordon Lethbridge-Stewart 扮演了很重要的角色
By then, he's a brigadier
with a remarkable active service record.
那时，他是一个准将, 有着出色的服役记录
And then he vanishes.
然后他就消失了
You must have known him
during your time with UNIT.
你肯定认识他，那段时间你也在UNIT
Sorry to disappoint you,
but I'm just a journalist.
让你们失望了，我只是一个记者
With no official records
of Lethbridge-Stewart,
由于没有关于 Lethbrige-Stewart 的官方记录
one could easily imagine he was dead.
其他人就会很轻易地认为他已经死了
UNIT looks after its own.
UNIT 会保护他们自己人
What's this brigadier
supposed to have done?
你们觉得这个准将都做了什么？
He has committed a great crime.
他犯了一项巨大的罪行
But there are other ways of seeking him.
但还是有其它方法找到他
(SPHERE BEEPING)
(BANG)
(PULSATING)
(SPHERE BEEPING AND PULSATING)
Someone in the secure system.
有人进入了安全系统
- What's happening?
- Daniel Hinton.
- 怎么回事？ - 是丹尼尔·辛顿
- That devious little...
- I don't want him hurt, Christopher.
- 那个狡猾的小...  - 我不想他受伤，克里斯托弗
Of course.
当然
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING
THROUGH HEADPHONES)
MAN: (ON RADIO) And that's the
Acoustic Hoods here at Top o'the Clock.
You're jacked into N Treble U
你收听的是 NTU 电台
from New World,
the people with the solution,
由有解决方案的人 - 新世界为你带来
and we ain't talking watered down here.
我们的节目不兑水
If you can't get your
head round life, no hassle.
如果你不能从生活中抬起头来，没有问题
There's over 300 different courses
here at New World.
新世界有300多种不同的课程
So there's got to be a right one for you,
hasn't there?
所以总有一款适合你，是吧？
Give us a call. 0135-66...
给我们来电话，0135-66...
There he is!
他在那儿！
(SPHERE BEEPING AND PULSATING)
What is New World University?
新世界大学是什么？
You don't have lectures.
You don't even have tutors.
你们没有讲座，你们连老师都没有
All the tuition is
conducted by the mainframe,
所有的授课都是由靠电脑主机来进行
a personalised syllabus for every student.
为每个学生提供个性化的教学大纲
Since when did computers get
personal?
电脑什么时候开始有个性了？
(BEEPING AND PULSATING)
Come on, what are the Chillys really for?
说说，鸡仔真正是干什么的
A sort of a fascist hippy cult?
一种法西斯嬉皮士邪教？
The wicked world is full of lost children,
the aimless, the lonely.
这个邪恶的世界里到处都是失落的孩子, 漫无目的, 孤独无助
We follow the Det-sen disciplines
which we share with our Chancellor.
我们遵循德赞信条，这点我们与校长是一致的
We really do care.
我们真的在意
Well, where is he then? Why can't I see him?
那，他在哪儿？我怎么见不到他？
The Chancellor sees no one.
校长不见任何人
He has taken the Path of Truth.
他已经走上了真理之路
Victoria Waterfield.
维多利亚•沃特菲尔德
That's you on the list, isn't it?
At the London Event?
在名单上的是你，对不？伦敦事件的时候
Oh, you must have been really young.
噢，你那时一定很年轻
Considering I was born
over 140 years ago...
考虑到我是140多年前出生的...
Peanuts, I used to know someone who...
花生，我以前认识一个能够-fixme
Oh, never mind.
噢，算了
Oh, sorry, I mean, no,
you don't look a day over...
哦，抱歉，我是说，你看起来一天也没有...
I don't feel a day over. (LAUGHING)
(COMPUTER READING ON LOOP)
Find the Locus.
找到人偶
(WHIMPERS)
We all have pain to face, Sarah,
我们都有痛苦要面对，莎拉
but the revelation will be soon.
但启示很快就会出现
(COMPUTER READING ON LOOP)
(SPHERE BEEPING AND PULSATING)
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING
THROUGH HEADPHONES)
Come on, Daniel.
来吧，丹尼尔
Nothing to be afraid of.
没什么可害怕的
We're here to help you.
我们是来帮你的
You've been chosen.
你被选中了
It's a sham!
这是假象！
The whole thing!
这整件事！
It'll get you all!
它会抓到你们所有人！
It already has you, Daniel.
它已经抓到你了，丹尼尔
Go on, then.
继续啊
There's no escape, not even that way.
你没法逃掉了，就是那边也不行
-(DANIEL SCREAMING)
-(WHISPERING) Daniel!
丹尼尔！
-(WIND HOWLING)
-(CROWD CHATTERING)
MAN: Ball!
球！
Sir? Please, sir?
长官？打扰了，长官
Hinton? What are you doing here?
辛顿？你在这里做什么？
Hinton, D.A., sir. School House 91.
辛顿, 地方检察官, 长官。学校房子91 fixme
It must be a good three years
since you got yourself expelled.
你被开除后这三年过得肯定很不错
Yes, sir, but I need to talk to you now.
Sir, It's important.
是的, 长官, 但我现在需要和你谈谈。 长官，很重要的事
Frankly, Hinton, I don't know
how you could throw it all away.
坦白说, 辛顿, 我不知道你怎么能把这一切都扔掉
You excel at maths and
computer work...
你擅长数学和计算机工作..
The headmaster says
I'm "a disruptive influence”.
校长说我“破坏性的影响”
It wasn't deliberate, sir.
这不是故意的，长官
No more than losing your CCF kit
or skiving off games.
(SIGHS) This occult nonsense.
这太荒诞了
Dabbling with black magic
is a dangerous business.
玩弄黑魔法太危险了
It was a séance, sir.
Not magic, or drugs.
那是个邪教，长官。没有魔法，没有磕药
- No?  - I've done it loads of times.
- 不是？ - 我已经做过好多次了
I suppose it's a gift.
我想这是种天份
You have no idea
what you're dealing with.
你完全不知道你在对付什么
No, sir. Not natural, is it?
不知道，长官。超自然的东西，对不？
Do you have a family, sir?
你有家庭吗，长官？
You realise we're under surveillance.
你意识到我们被监视了吧
Tsk. Wretched boy.
唉, 可怜的男孩
(DISTORTED) Where is the Locus?
人偶在哪儿？
Who are you?
你是谁？
(MONSTER GROWLING)
(STATIC)
ANSWERING MACHINE: This is Alistair
Lethbridge-Stewart at Brendon.
这里是布伦登的Alistair
Lethbridge-Stewart家
Leave your name, number
and message after the tone,
在嘀的一声后，留下你的名字、电话和留言
and I'll call you back
as soon as possible.
我会尽快给你打回去的
(ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS)
WOMAN: Oh, hello, er, Brigadier?
This is the headmaster's secretary.
噢，你好，准将。这里是校长秘书处
We were concerned
that you missed the meeting
你没来参加，我们很关切
about your retirement party this morning.
今早是你的退休欢送会
We've also had several rather
strange phone enquiries about you.
我们还接到几个奇怪的电话，都是在问你的问题
Could you get in touch ASAP?
Thank you.
你能尽快与我们联系吗，谢谢
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
I thought I was in Cromer.
我以为我在克罗默fixme
-(STATIC STOPS)
-(CROWD CHATTERING)
Tuesday?
星期二了？
(ANSWERING MACHINE REWINDING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
KATE: Look, erm, it's me, Dad.
是这样，嗯，是我，爸爸
- I'm sorry, I know it's been a long time.
- Kate!
- 我很抱歉，我知道太长时间了  - 凯特！
This'll be a shock and all that...
but can I see you?
这很突然而且又...但我能见你吗？
Soon please, Dad.
尽快好吗，爸爸
Sorry. It's, erm, 0585-226-904.
抱歉，我的号码是0585-226-904
Erm, thanks. (BEEPS)
嗯，谢谢
(ANSWERING MACHINE)
Saturday, 3:44 p.m.
星期六，下午 3:44
Stupid machine.
Can't have been asleep that long.
愚蠢的机器。我不可能睡了那么久
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(BEEPS)
MALE VOICE:
Greyhound is asked to call Trap Six.
有要求让灰狗呼叫陷阱六号
(灰狗 Greyhound 是 UNIT 中一个小组的代号，Brigadier 自己是灰狗一号）
I repeat, Greyhound is to call Trap Six.
重复一遍，灰狗将呼叫陷阱六号
- ANSWERING MACHINE: Monday, 10:05 a.m.
- Monday? What ever happened to Sunday?
- 星期一，上午 10:05  - 星期一？星期天哪儿去了？
(SCOFFS) Nonsense.
No one sleeps for three days.
胡扯，没人能一觉睡三天
(PHONE RINGING)
-(STATIC)
- Brendon School.
这里是布伦登学校
Who is this?
是哪位？
SARAH: Hello? Brigadier?
你好，准将吗？
- This is Sarah-Jane Smith.
- Miss Smith?
- 我是莎拉-简·史密斯  - 史密斯小姐？
Yes. Look, just please listen.
You could be in danger.
是的。请听我说，你可能有危险
I've just come from
New World University...
我刚从新世界大学出来...
-(STATIC) -Hello? Brigadier!
能听到吗？准将！
-(PULSATING)
-(PLAYING ON LOOP) Brendon school.
We have him.
我们找到他了
Hi, kids. Been in
any good deprograms lately?
嗨, 孩子们。最近有什么好的节目吗？
Want any autographs?
想要谁的签名不？
If you can read, that is.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Looking for something, Anthony?
- A producer with a sense of humour.
- 在找什么吗，安东尼？  - 找一个有幽默感的制作人
-(CHUCKLES)
- I want a word with the high priestess.
我想和高级女祭司说句话
I'm afraid the vice chancellor's busy.
恐怕副校长这会儿正忙
The conviction I give your propagandist
crap should win me a BAFTA.
I can't get into my office
for ruddy computer hardware.
Well, it's all part of the new
automated transmitter programme.
- Then get the transmitter
to read the scripts. (CHUCKLES)
There's no people left here.
这里都没有人了
It's just computers
and brain-dead Chillys.
只有电脑和无脑的鸡仔
I'll tell Miss Waterfield.
我会同沃特菲尔德小姐讲的
Tell her I want action now.
告诉她我要看见行动
Not when orders come down from our
Glorious Sponsor, wherever he hangs out.
DISTORTED VOICE: This blind,
empty outer-darkness is unendurable!
这个盲目的, 空虚的外面黑暗是无法忍受的!
Release me now!
释放我吧！
I gave you my word. Soon.
我向你承诺过了，快了
(SIGHS) I don't belong in this world.
我不属于这个世界
My family and friends, all lost in time.
我的家庭和朋友，都迷失在时间里了
We are both outcast, Victoria.
我们都是被放逐的人，维多利亚
That is why we work together.
所以我们要携手
I built you this place,
我给你建了这个地方
with the money my dear
father invested 130 years ago
用了我父亲130年前投资所产生的收益
In return, you promised us
the Light of Truth.
作为回报，你许诺给我们真相之光
(SCOFFS) There is no Light.
没有光
I trust you, Victoria.
我相信你，维多利亚
One Locus still binds my power.
还有一个人偶困住我的能力
The others were dealt with.
其它的都已经处理掉了
The last must... Will be ready for my
return.
最后一个必须...为我的回归做好准备
I think I'm going to scream.
我觉得我要尖叫了
Trap Six, this is Greyhound.
What is your message?
{STATIC)
{INDISTINCT)
Please repeat, Trap Six.
It's an appalling line.
请再说一遍，陷阱六号。这信息很震惊
In London?
在伦敦吗？
Roger, Trap Six, message understood.
收到，陷阱六号，明白了
(ENERGY PULSATING)
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
The brigadier's on the move...
准将出动了...
Daniel Hinton?
丹尼尔·辛顿呢？
He fell from the roof.
他从屋顶上掉下去了
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
Just jumped.
There's no sign of him below.
他跳下去了，但下面没有见到他的踪迹
But no one could...
但没人能...
Why didn't you tell me?
你怎么不早告诉我？
Poor Daniel. We must find him!
可怜的丹尼尔。我们必须找到他！
Let me explain again.
让我再解释一下
He's vanished.
His programme's ring-fenced.
He cannot deprogram himself.
Horrible modern terms. You deal with it.
可怕的现代术语。你来处理吧
My task is to prepare the way.
Not found the Locus yet then?
还没有找到人偶吗？
Christopher, the chancellor is coming home.
克里斯托弗, 校长要回来了
VICTORIA: It seems the time is now.
看来现在到时候了
I must find the last Locus
我必须找到最后一个人偶
before Daniel's misguided hopes
wreck everything we've worked for.
免得被误导的丹尼尔会破坏我们为之奋斗的一切
Bleeding loaded.
Let it go, will ya? I was only looking!
放手吧，行吗？我只是看看
(WHISPERS) God.
老天
(SIGHS)
(HORN HONKING)
The Locus...
那个人偶...
I'll break your fingers, you little...
我要掰断你的手指，你个小...
(FOOTSTEPS)
No, no... (MUFFLED GRUNTING)
不，不...
(HORNS BLARING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
- I'm trying to get through there,
but it's worse. - Yeah. Excuse me...
- 我本打算从这边过去，但更不好走  - 是，抱歉...
It's coming closer.
它越来越近了
Perhaps you have
something it needs, sir.
也许你手里有它要的东西
After all this time?
I rather doubt that, Hinton.
这么些年以后？我很是怀疑，辛顿
But you remember
what it was, don't you?
但你记得是什么东西，对吗？
BRIGADIER: I'm not as blinkered
as people think.
我并不像人们想象的那么睁眼瞎
It's a sort of mind parasite.
它像是一种意识寄生虫
- The first alien force I ever came up against.
- Sir?
- 是我第一次遭遇的外星力量  - 长官？
In those days it called itself
The Great Intelligence.
那个时候它自称为“大智慧”
And?
还有呢？
No physical shape of its own,
so it enslaved humans as pawns.
它没有它自己的物理形体, 所以它就奴役人类作为它的爪牙
And it deployed a squad of strategic
robots camouflaged like Yeti.
它还部署了一队战斗机器人, 伪装成雪怪的样子
Was this in Tibet, sir?
那是在西藏吗, 长官？
No. London, about 25 years ago.
不, 伦敦, 大概25年前
It invaded the city like a virus,
它像病毒一样入侵了这个城市
using the Underground network
as its nervous system.
把地铁网络用作了它的神经系统
Grisly business.
I thought we were rid of the blighter.
可怕的事情。我以为我们已经摆脱这个可恶的家伙了
It's still here, sir,
它还在这里, 长官
out on the bardo, the astral plane,
躲在中阴之中, 五行之外
（中阴：藏传佛教术语, 指灵魂处于死后与重生之间时的状态）
trapped outside our physical existence.
被困于我们物理存在之外
BRIGADIER: Is it indeed?
确实吗？
And what does it want?
那它想要什么？
I don't know, sir.
我不知道, 长官
It's you it's hunting.
它在追寻的是你
(GASPS)
What's this got to do with you, Hinton?
但这怎么又跟你扯上了关系, Hinton？
Just don't trust anyone, sir.
别相信任何人, 长官
- What?  - No one at all.
- 什么？ - 无论是谁
Look, I'll thank you, Hinton,
not to treat me like a complete idiot.
嗯, 我得感谢你, Hinton, 没把我当做一个完全的傻子
(HORNS BLARING)
(YETI GROWLING)
Damn traffic. Brings out the worst
in you, doesn't it?
可恶的交通, 把每个人最坏的一面都带出来了, 是吧？
(HORN HONKING)
DISTORTED VOICE: Daniel Hinton.
丹尼尔·辛顿
You are summoned.
你被召唤了
(WHIMPERING) Sir, get off me!
先生, 离我远点！
Daniel Hinton!
丹尼尔·辛顿
My summons binds you!
我召唤你！
MAN: (ON RADIO) Traffic update
on New World FM.
新世界FM播报交通状况
ANTHONY: (ON RADIO) I think you'd
better stay home today.
我觉得你们最好今天待在家里
On top of a ton of traffic probs,
除了一大堆交通堵塞
they've just announced that all the
railways and major airports are suspended.
他们刚刚还宣布了铁路和主要机场都关闭
So, you'd better get walking 'cause
they're shutting down the tube, too.
所以你最好步行, 因为他们又要关闭隧道了
Crazy. Everything has computer flu.
疯了, 所有东西都患上了电脑病毒似的
(招牌文字: 电脑混沌在蔓延)
So, whatever you do, don't log into your PCs.
所以, 不管你干什么, 今天都不要登入电脑
They're in a mean mood today.
(ALARM CHIRPS)
它们今天心情很不爽
Can I tell you about the New World, sir?
我能跟你介绍一下新世界吗, 先生？
I'm not interested.
我不感兴趣
We want to tell you
about our good news, sir.
我们想跟你说说我们的好消息, 先生
I said I'm not interested.
我说了我不感兴趣
Have a better one.
找个更好的吧(fixme)
And that's the best of the weather,
brought to you by New World University
这是最好的天气, 新世界大学为你们带来
where the sun always shines.
而阳光永远灿烂
Gridlock out there.
外面交通大堵塞
Is it Friday the 13th,
and they didn't tell us?
难道今天是黑色星期五, 而他们没有告诉我们？
Stay at home, give us a call.
待在家里, 给我们打电话
0135-666-416.
And on line one, it's Danny.
一号线接通了, 这位是丹尼
Hi, Daniel. What's your problem?
嗨, 丹尼尔, 你什么问题？
HINTON: Anthony, it's me. I'm still alive.
安东尼, 是我, 我还活着
- Listen. It's coming.
- Danny, you idiot. What's happening?
- 听我说, 它要来了  - 丹尼, 你个笨蛋, 都怎么回事？
It's already coming for me,
but it wants all of us.
它已经来找我了, 但它要我们全部
- You've got to warn...
- I knew you'd get caught! Where are you?
- 你必须得警告...  - 我就知道你会被抓住的！你在哪儿？
Danny, you've got to get help before we...
丹尼, 你必须找人帮忙, 否则我们...
Danny! Danny!
丹尼！丹尼！
(ENERGY PULSATING)
{STATIC)
{GROANING)
-(SIGHS)
- What are you after?
你在追什么？
Bloody Chillys.
要命的鸡杂
- I'm going to get the law.
- Think they'd believe you?
- 我打算去找执法部门了  - 觉得他们会相信你？
Sir, I never hurt no one.
先生, 我从没伤害过任何人
Not me, sir. Not old Harrods.
不是过, 先生, 不是老哈罗斯
(SHOUTS) Don't!
不要！
Sir,
先生
flew right down, you did.
飞下来了, 你那时候
Glided down out of that place. (LAUGHS)
从哪个地方滑下来了
Don't need jets no more, sir?
不在需要滑翔机了吗, 先生？
And then he comes after us,
like an old spidery man.
然后他就开始追着我们, 像一只老蜘蛛
He's coming after all of us.
他在追我们所有人
Listen, that money you nicked from me
is no good to anyone. Period!
听着, 你从我身上摸走的钱对谁也没有好处。句号！
Not unless you help me!
除非你帮助我？
You got more?
你还有吗？
Sir, 1 got principles.
先生, 我有原则的
I'm very particular.
我非常挑剔
You've seen what's coming,
你看到什么东西会来
but it's only half what I see.
但不及我说看到的一半
Come on, there's someone
we have to reach fast.
快, 我们必须得尽快找到一个人
- Good morning.
- Hi. How can I help you?
- 早上好  - 嗨, 有什么可以帮你的吗？
Lethbridge-Stewart for Cavendish.
利斯布里奇-斯图尔特, 来找凯文迪许
Right. If you'd like to go through
to the lounge, Brigadier,
好, 如果你走过休息室, 准将
you'll find Captain Cavendish
already waiting for you.
你就会发现凯文迪许队长已经在等你
"John Jerum, soldierman,
Is searching high and low.
"John Jerum, 兵哥哥, 上下求索"
"The only secret he can keep
Is one he doesn't know.”
“唯一能保住的秘密, 是他自己也不知道的”
My father used to say that.
我父亲经常念这句
He'd have hated this.
他肯定恨这个
You haven't got a clue, have you?
你一点都不知道, 是吧
Your precious Chancellor's
got all the real power,
你那宝贵的校长拥有所有真正的能力
the power we can all profit by.
我们都可以从这些能力里受益
He isn't just some
father substitute for you.
他可不是你那什么父亲的小替身
He works for the world's spiritual good,
他致力于建立一个很好的精神世界
but you'd even sell your own soul.
但你却把自己的灵魂都卖了
(CHUCKLES) That's marketing.
这是市场营销
All "ring-fenced” no doubt.
Like your expense account.
ANTHONY: (LOUDSPEAKERS)
Victoria Waterfield!
维多利亚•沃特菲尔德!
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Miss Waterfield's our boss,
ladies and gentlemen,
沃特菲尔德小姐是我们的老板, 女士们先生们
- the big cheese at N Treble U!
- Make him stop! Stop him!
- 她是 NTU 的重要任务！  - 让他停下来！阻止他！
-(CHUCKLES)
- And she's today's surprise guest
她是今天的神秘嘉宾
on “Lift the Lid.”
来到“揭开盖子”栏目
So, ring in those questions now.
好, 现在打电话进来提问吧
It's revelation time, Vice Chancellor!
到了揭晓的时间了, 副校长！
Forget anything I said before.
It was lies!
忘了我以前说过的话吧, 都是谎言！
New World's just a big front.
新世界只是一个大幌子
But they pay well, don't they,
Miss Waterfield?
不过他们薪水不错, 是吧, 沃特菲尔德小姐？
-(ENERGY PULSATING) - What about
all the people that disappear, eh?
但那些失踪的人呢, 嗯？
Danny was right!
丹尼说对了！
New World doesn't give a toss for you.
新世界并不在乎你
Something's coming.
有东西来了
Victoria Waterfield will tell you.
维多利亚•沃特菲尔德会告诉你们的
(SOBBING) She'll tell you.
她会告诉你们
And it'll finish everything.
那东西会结束这一切
- Good to see you, Brigadier.
- Sorry I'm late, Cavendish.
- 很高兴见到你, 准将  - 抱歉我来晚了, 凯文迪许
The transport system seems to be
fouled up by this computer business.
交通系统似乎被电脑问题搞瘫痪了
- Mmm, quite. Would you care for a drink?
- No, thank you.
- 唔, 太差了。你介意喝一杯吗？  - 不, 谢谢你
I thought it best to meet here.
我觉得在这里见面最好
Security boys get a bit stressed out
over ID checks.
负责安全的小伙子们总是要紧张兮兮地查证件
So, UNIT hasn't changed since my time, eh?
看来, 我走之后 UNIT 还没变, 嗯？
Well, I doubt there'd be much left
that you'd recognise.
哦, 我怀疑还有多少你能认识
Razor-smart weapons,
all are computers these days.
Razor-smart 的武器, 现在全是电脑了fixme
I used to leave the technology to the
experts.
我那时都把技术问题留给专家
Yes, of course.
是, 当然
Do you know they called your era
"The Blunder Days"?
你知道他们把你们那个时代叫做“Blunder时代”吗？
- The what?
- Blood and Thunder.
- 什么时代？  - 热血和雷霆
Well, you took on
some formidable opposition.
看, 你碰上了一些强硬的对手
Cybermen, demons, Yeti.
赛博人, 恶魔, 雪怪
No worse than jumped up officers
with tuppenny-halfpenny commissions.
Right.
对
Cavendish, exactly why did you call me
up to town today?
凯文迪许, 你今天到底是为了什么把我叫进城来？
Information, sir,
资料, 长官
of a personal nature, you understand?
Meaning?
意思是...？
Someone's been hacking
into security files in Geneva.
有人黑进了日内瓦的保密文件
My files, I take it.
我的文件, 我懂了
Yes, so the MOD were never very
forthcoming about dealings with UNIT.
是的, 所有
Besides, we need more personal details.
另外, 我们需要多一些个人信息
We?
我们？
Do I take it that security is in the dark
about this, too?
Strange you never rose
above Brigadier, wasn't it?
奇怪的是你做准将之后再也没有升值过, 是吗？
Internal politics.
内部政治
Well, I had no idea there was a market
for my memoirs.
啊, 我还不知道我的回忆录还挺有市场
I'll send you a copy
when I get round to writing them.
等我有时间写完的话, 我会送你一本
So, UNIT got all the blame
for blowing up the church.
所以, 炸掉教堂的事情就全是 UNIT 背锅了？fixme
(CHUCKLES)
- Are you sure you won't join me, Brigadier?
- Quite sure.
- 你确定不陪我来一杯, 准将？ - 相当确定
You must've picked up
the odd souvenir in your time.
你那时肯定拿过一些奇怪的东西
I counted them in
and I counted them all back out.
收进来的时候我数过, 放回去的时候我哦也数过
No particular keepsake?
没有什么特别的纪念品？
I mean, things do get mislaid.
我是说, 弄丢什么东西
If you lose things,
you could lose men, too.
如果你弄丢东西, 你也会弄丢人
Well, it's been good to talk to you, Cavendish.
but I have another appointment.
好了, 很高兴同你聊聊。凯文迪许。但我还有另外一个约
So soon? I was concerned, Brigadier.
这么快？我很担心, 准将？
- So was I
- CAVENDISH: So you should be.
- 我也是  - 你也该这样
Blood and Thunder, Captain.
热血与雷霆, 队长fixme
Now back off.
现在退后
I'm leaving.
我走了
Get after him!
去追他！
It's not too late!
还不算太迟！
I must find it.
我必须找到它
(PYRAMID PULSATING)
DISTORTED VOICE: Victoria, I am here.
维多利亚, 我在这里
(DISTORTED) Where is the Locus?
人偶在哪里？
(HORNS BLARING)
All right then.
Quote them the codes, NN and then QQ.
那好吧, 告诉他们代号, NN 和 QQ
(分别指《可恶的雪人》和《恐惧之网》对应事件,
其实它们是相应电视剧集的生产代号)
It's a risk, but we must reach
someone we can trust.
这是个风险, 但我们必须找到一个我们可以信任的人
(STATIC)
- MAN: (ON PHONE) Q?
- No, I said codes NN and Q... QQ!
- Q?  - 不, 我说了, 代号是 NN 和 Q .. QQ！
- It's urgent!
- I see, thank you.
- 这事很紧急！  - 明白了, 谢谢你
I'd get more sense from a tea lady.
找个女服务员都比你明白
May I ask if you've encountered
anything resembling a Yeti?
我可以问问, 你是遇到了某种像是雪怪的东西？
- Have I encountered any what?
- A Yeti.
- 我是遇到了什么？ - 雪怪！
What have Yeti got to do with it?
雪怪跟这有什么关系？
- You're late.
- I was delayed.
- 你迟到了  - 我被拖住了
The traffic and this computer business...
堵车和电脑方面的问题...
- Are you all right?
- Oh, I can't complain.
- 你还好吗？  - 噢, 没什么可抱怨的
How are you?
你好吗？
Look, this is stupid.
看, 这事很愚蠢
I'll just go. I shouldn't have called you.
我还是走吧, 不应该给你打电话的
Look, Kate, have you eaten?
We could get a meal.
嗯, 凯特, 你吃了吗？我们可以去吃个饭
No. Ugh...
不, 呃...
- All right, er, we'll sit here.
- 1... (SIGHS)
- 没事, 嗯, 我们就这里坐坐  - 我...
I'm sorry, Dad.
对不起, 爸爸
You look tired.
你看起来很累
I've had a difficult morning.
我这一早上过得很糟糕
Kate, it's been six years.
凯特, 这都六年了
What's the matter? Is it money?
出什么事呢？是因为钱吗？
No, no. Not especially.
不, 不。并不是
- Your mother then?
- No! I don't see her either.
- 那是你母亲？  - 不！我也没见她
Look, I know this is crazy, but...
看, 我知道
- I'm being harassed.
- Who by?
- 我被骚扰了  - 被谁？
- There are these Chillys.
- Chillys?
- 就那些鸡仔  - 鸡仔?
- You know? Children...
-(EXCLAIMS) Children?
- 你知道吗, 一些孩子...  - 孩子？
I mean they're called Children
from this New World techno-cult.
我是说他们被一个新世界的科技崇拜团队称为孩子
Two of them.
有两个人
They just sit opposite the boat
all the time.
他们一直坐在船的对面
- Look, I'm being stupid.
- No.
- 看, 我是个蠢人...  - 不
But they just won't go away.
但他们就是不走
And they're frightening...
And they're frightening me.
而且他们很吓人...他们让我害怕了
Chancellor.
校长
Welcome home, Professor Travers.
欢迎回来, Travers 教授
(DISTORTED) I am still in the wilderness.
还还在荒野里
Only my will to survive
keeps me from despair.
都靠我求生的欲望才使我免于绝望
You have lit a flame of hope in all of us.
你在我们中间点起了希望的火焰
It is as I instructed.
它是按照我的指示
Symmetry. Shape.
对称. 形状
My form at last,
最后是我的形体
shaping out my future!
决定了我的未来！
When will my new web
stretch out across the Earth?
什么时候我的新网才能布满整个地球？
Web?
网？
Only when I have found the final Locus!
只有等我找到最后的人偶！
But what about, erm...
但那个谁, 嗯...
What's his name? Doesn't he help?
他的名字是什么来着？他帮不上忙吗？
I split up with Jonathan two years ago.
我同乔纳森分开了, 两年前
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm getting old.
我老了
Perhaps you should get off that boat.
也许你应该离开那艘船
It's not the boat. It's them!
问题不是船, 是他们！
- And me too?
- Well,
- 我也是吗？  - 怎么说呢
army families get to live together,
so why didn't we?
军人家庭一般都住在一起, 为什么我们不是？
Was your career that important?
你的事业就那么重要？
I'm afraid I can't explain, Kate.
恐怕我没法解释, 凯特
Mum used to think that
you were some sort of spy.
妈妈曾经以为, 你是某种间谍
We used to hope it, because at least
that would be interesting.
我们曾经都盼望过, 因为那样的话就会很有意思
But it's just soldiers, isn't it?
但你只是一个士兵, 是吗？
Training to kill people with big guns.
被训练成用大枪去杀人
I had other responsibilities.
我扛着其它一些责任
Well, who to?
哦, 对谁的责任？
To everyone.
对每一个人
What?
什么？
That's all.
只能说这么多
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Who do I trust, then?
那, 我信任谁？
Don't trust anyone, sir.
I told you, no one at all.
别相信任何人, 长官。我告诉过你, 无论是谁
Are you sure you don't want any money?
你确定不想要些钱吗？
Oh, just forget it then.
噢, 忘了这事算了
Kate. Kate, wait!
凯特, 凯特, 等等！
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING THROUGH HEADPHONES)
Hello again, Granddad. We want you.
又遇到了, 老爷爷, 我们在找你
Argh!
啊！
Good Lord...
好家伙...
Is that you?
是你吗？
Have you changed yourself again?
你又变样子了？
（显然这里准将以为这又是博士的新化身）
Om mani padme hum
(唵嘛呢叭咪吽)
I needed time!
我需要时间!
DISTORTED VOICE: I needed freedom!
我需要自由！
You're not Professor Travers!
你不是 Travers 教授！
-(LAUGHING)
- A pity shame!
可怜可耻！fixme
Let me go!
放开我！
Your task is done.
你的任务完成了
Now, I take control!
现在, 我掌握控制权了
Let me go!
放开我
Who are you?
你是谁？
Remember me, Victoria?
记得我吗, 维多利亚？
Who's blind now?
现在谁是瞎子？
- Hello, Dad.  - Kate.
- 嗨, 爸爸  - 凯特
- Where am I?  - On the boat.
- 我在哪儿？  - 在船上
We had to bring you here.
我们只能带你来这里
Daniel Hinton, Brigadier. School House 91.
我是丹尼尔·辛顿, 准将。布伦登学校91届
I remember. Thank you.
我记得。谢谢你
But we met quite recently. Am I right?
但我们最近碰过面, 我说得对吗？
On something called the astral plane?
在一个被称为意识层面的地方？
It wasn't entirely wasted then.
看来没有全白费
Extraordinary.
令人惊奇
Hello? We're moving.
怎么？我们在走
Dad, I thought it would be best if...
爸爸, 我觉得最好还是...
Sir... Glad to see you're all right, sir.
长官...很高兴看见你没事, 长官
Harrods saved you from the Chillys.
哈罗斯从鸡仔手中救了你
Bunch of hooligans, sir.
一群小流氓而已, 长官
Best off well away from them.
最好离他们远一点
Well, thank you, erm... Harrods?
好, 谢谢你, 呃...哈罗斯？
Sir.
是
Army, aren't you? On your uppers?
军人, 对不？在你鞋帮上fixme
RAF, sir. Flight Sergeant Haroldson.
Squadron got disbanded, sir.
皇家空军, 长官。空军上士哈罗德森。中队编制被取消了, 长官
Like losing your family.
就像没了家一样
Get called Harrods
'cause I'm fussy where I kip down.
被叫做哈罗斯, 因为我对于睡觉的地方很挑剔
- Alright, Flight Sergeant. Carry on.
- Sir.
- 好吧, 空军上士, 继续  - 是
I must say, Kate,
the company you keep's an eye-opener.
我必须要说, 凯特, 你这些朋友很让人开眼
Oh, I thought they were with you.
哦, 我还以为他们是你一伙儿的
We can't stay here, Brigadier,
the Intelligence is hunting us.
我们不能待在这里, 准将。大智慧在搜寻我们
The both of us? Are you one of these
Chilly characters too?
我们两个都是？你不也是那些鸡仔中的一员吗？
New World's a front to bring
the Intelligence back through,
新世界只是一个外壳, 意图是要把大智慧带回来
an evil spirit that
got bound to the Earth.
那是个恶灵, 被困到地球了
Listen to you two. I mean, who do I
call first, police or psychiatrist?
听听你们两个。我是说, 我应该先打电话给谁, 警察还是精神病医生？
Trust no one. Isn't that right, Hinton?
别信任何人。这没错吧, 辛顿？
- Not even my people at the UNIT.
- The whole city's fouled up.
- 即使是我那些 UNIT 的人  - 整个城市都混乱了
The computer Internet's virally infested.
电脑互联网已经被病毒入侵了
And that's the Intelligence's new body?
那就是大智慧的新形体？
It won't stop there.
它不会止步于此的
(BEEPING)
The Intelligence was driven out.
I was there.
大智慧被赶走了, 当时我在那里
No. It's trapped until all its old
icons of power can be destroyed.
没有, 它只是被困住了。fixme
One link still remains, the final Locus.
有一个链接还在, 最后那个人偶
- Well, how do you know?
- Just do.
- 哦, 你怎么知道？  - 就是知道
Cavendish asked me about keepsakes.
卡文迪许问过我是否保留了纪念品
And now that I think of it,
现在我再想想
- there was something.
- Yes?
- 好像是有某个东西  - 是吗？
But I lost that years ago.
但多年以前弄丢了
Like what?
什么样子的？
A small carving of a Yeti,
like a chess piece.
一个雪怪一样的小雕像, 像一个象棋棋子
Tibetan, I think.
西藏的东西, 我想是
Dad...
爸爸...
(BEEPING)
Like this?
就像这个？
Yes. That's it.
是的, 就是它
I've had it since I was little.
我很小的时候拿了它
It's infinitely dangerous.
We must get rid of it now.
这东西非常的危险, 我们必须马上甩掉它
(CRASHING)
Sir?
长官？
Sir, we have company.
长官, 有客人来了
No, get them away! Get them away!
不, 把他们弄走！把他们弄走！
- Everyone, out, now!
- I'm sorry, Brigadier.
- 所有人, 出去, 马上！  - 抱歉, 准将
Out of the way, Hinton.
别碍事, 辛顿
I didn't know, I swear it.
我不知道, 我发誓
What are you on about?
你这是干什么？
I warned you! Don't trust anyone!
我告诉过你！不要相信任何人！
The Intelligence used me to seek you out.
I'm the trap!
大智慧利用我来把你挖出来, 我就是诱饵！
I'm warning you, Hinton, stand back!
我警告你, 辛顿, 后退！
- Give me the Locus.
- KATE: No.
- 把人偶给我  - 不
No guns. Not here!
不要开枪, 这里不行！
- Get back!
-(BEEPING)
后退!
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
What's happening? This is my home.
发生了什么？这里是我家
Well, they got what they want
and now they're going.
喏, 他们得到了他们想要的东西, 现在就撤了
Back to the New World, sir.
回新世界去了, 长官
That's where it all comes from.
他们都来自那个地方
What sort of job do you do?
你干的是什么工作？
- That boy...
- I have to get after them, Kate.
- 那个孩子...  - 我必须得去追他们, 凯特
I'll explain later.
我后面再解释
Just go, then.
走吧, 那就
Flight Sergeant?
空军上士？
I'll come, sir. For the lad's sake.
我也去, 长官。为了那个小伙子
Good man.
好人
Er, wait outside, will you?
呃, 外面等一下, 好吗？
Sir.
是
- Kate.
- What?
- 凯特  - 什么？
Just tell me one thing.
就告诉我一件事情
Why do you keep a box of toys down there?
为什么你在这里存了一箱玩具？
He'll be five, next week.
他就要满五岁了, 下个星期
(SOFTLY) I have a grandson!
我有一个外孙了！
My grandson!
我的孙子！
I never dreamt...
我从没梦想过...
Good Lord.
好家伙
Gordon.
他叫戈登
Gordon James, after you.
戈登-詹姆斯, 用你的名取得
He's safe, away from here.
他很安全, 不在这里
Oh, I'm sorry.
哦, 对不起
(SNIFFLES) My grandson.
我的外孙
Kate, can I keep this?
凯特, 我能留着这个吗？
It's getting late.
时候不早了
We'll talk later. I'll be back.
我们晚些再谈, 我会回来的
(GROWLING)
(DISTORTED) At last.
终于
I created this tiny object
我创造了这个小东西
and it has bound me in darkness.
而它把我困在了黑暗中
Which of you shall release me?
你们谁来释放我？
(EXPLODING)
Light...
光...
(GROANING)
Symmetry of colours and shapes.
对称的颜色和形状
No more tomb of darkness.
不再有黑暗的坟墓了
My strength is growing again.
我的力量又开始增长了
I grasp it.
我抓住了
Now let my great plan take its shape.
现在让我的伟大计划成形吧
(ENERGY PULSATING)
(ALL CHANTING) Om mani padme hum.
唵嘛呢叭咪吽
TRAVERS: (NORMAL VOICE)
I had a daughter once.
我曾经又一个女儿
What... What happened to her?
怎么...她后来怎么了？
Father?
父亲？
No, no. Not you. Anne.
不, 不, 不是你。安娜
(CHUCKLES)
Yeti...Travers...I...
雪怪...Travers...我...
I brought it...
我带回了它...
...back from Tibet.
...从西藏带来
It's all my fault.
这都是我的错
My father died in a cold world,
我的父亲死在了一个冰冷的世界
（她父亲死在 Daleks 母星 Skaro）
a thousand light years away.
一千光年以外
I died 15 years ago.
我15年前就死了
Saw it in The Times.
我在《时代》杂志上看到了
"Professor Edward Travers,”
“爱德华-特拉弗斯教授”
CBE.
大英帝国勋章(fixme)
Silly old fool.
老糊涂
(CHUCKLING)
"No flowers, by request.”
“应家属请求, 不要送花”
But they still sent them.
但他们还是送来了花
No one listens.
都不听
Sometimes I can't remember his face.
有时我记不起他的面容
And I've travelled in time.
但我穿越了时间
Where do I belong now?
我现在属于什么地方？
Don't you see?
你不明白吗？
We've been tricked.
我们被耍了
It was the Intelligence all the time!
一直都是大智慧
Unfinished business.
它未尽的事业(fixme)
(BOOMING)
(LIGHTNING CRASHING)
(Terminal Accessed)
（电脑文字：终端访问已接入）
What now, sir?
Take the place by storm?
现在怎样，长官？fixme
If we must.
如果必须的话
Damnation. I'm an old fool.
见鬼，我真是老糊涂了
- Sir?  - My gun.
- 怎么  - 我的枪
I didn't pick it up.
我没拿起来
- Want to go back?
- Too late for that, now. Come on.
- 想回去吗？  - 来不及了。现在走吧
(DISTORTED) Intruders.
有人入侵
Go. Greet them.
去，问候一下他们
(ENERGY PULSATING)
Sir, something rotten
in here, sir. I can feel it.
长官，这里有什么东西坏掉了，我能感觉到
Too quiet. Come on.
太安静。快来
Let's start at the top.
我们先从上面开始
Sorry, sir.
抱歉，长官
1 give up, Hinton.
Am I asleep or are you dead?
我放弃了，辛顿。是我在睡觉还是你死了？
I never did philosophy, sir.
我不玩哲学，长官
You're in the lift.
I'm in the computer systems.
你在电梯里，我在电脑系统里
We have interface.
我们就有了交互界面
So I'm talking to a ghost in a machine.
这么说我是在跟机器里面的一个鬼魂说话
And what's the warning this time?
这次又是什么警告？
The Intelligence has got into the
logic systems of New World's computers.
大智慧已经进入新世界的电脑系统了
I snuck a ride too.
我也偷偷搭便车
It's a virus. It's already spreading
across the Internet.
是一种病毒，已经散布到整个因特网了
Transmitted from this building.
是从这栋建筑传送出去的
I'll take you in as far as
I can, sir. Trust me.
我尽力带你进去，相信我
You've said that before.
你以前也说过这话
Sir?
长官？
Nothing, Sergeant.
I just walked over someone's grave.
没什么，上士。我刚碰到鬼了
Come on, Hinton! Come on!
快啊，辛顿！快点
- I thought that you were dead.
- Maybe.
- 我以为你已经死了  - 也许
I need your help, Kate.
So does your dad.
我需要你的帮助，凯特，你爸爸也需要
Right.
好
It's no good, sir. Something's jamming it.
这没用的，被什么东西卡住了
I'm not used to this system.
我不熟悉这个系统
But I am.
但我熟
Ever heard of automatic writing?
Fingers on the keys.
听说过知道写文章吗？把手指放上去
(HOUSE MUSIC PLAYING
THROUGH HEADPHONES)
HINTON: Something's moving that lift.
有什么东西在控制那个电梯
Option. A-D-stroke-Alt-three. Hit four.
Option键，A-D，敲Alt-3，按4
It's like a morgue, sir.
像个停尸房，长官
Like a trap.
像是个陷阱
Back the other way.
回去那边
HINTON: Stop that lift!
停掉那个电梯
Option, three-stroke-Alt-four.
Option键，Alt-4敲三遍
Brigadier, Get back!
准将，回去！
You...
你...
Get out of my head.
滚出我的脑袋
I've had enough of your tricks.
我已经受够了你的伎俩
I was wrong. Please!
我之前错了，求你了！
Get away from the lift!
离开那个电梯！
It's fighting back.
它在反击了
Alt-four again. Hold it down!
再按 Alt-4。按住了
Come away, please, Brigadier.
You shouldn't have come here.
你走吧, 准将。你不该来这里的
It's a bit late for apologies, Madam.
现在道歉晚了点吧，女士
Hold it there!
按住了！
I can't keep it down.
我按不住了
Go back to your studies.
回去继续学习
There's nothing here you want!
这里没有你们想要的东西
(THUDDING)
Quickly.
快
This way.
这边
HARRODS: Look out, sir!
小心，长官！
Leave him alone!
放开他！
Hold it down!
按住！
(BANG)
(ROARING)
TRAVERS: Acolytes! You know me!
助手们，你们认识我的！
Stand away!
都闪开！
Travers?
Release him! Let him go free!
放开他！让他走！
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
Must shut down the database.
必须关闭数据库了
VICTORIA: Leave him alone!
放开他！
(ROARING)
All right. I was coming anyway.
好吧。反正我也会来的
DISTORTED VOICE: What happened
to your faith, old man?
你的信念怎么了，老头？
Huh? I saw your
Light of Truth, that's what!
哈？我见过你的真理之光，这就是怎么了
And I'll put a stop to it!
我必须叫停它！
-(GASPS)
- More intruders, as anticipated.
又有入侵者，比预期要多
(ALL ROARING)
Travers... (LAUGHING)
You're still my closest instrument!
你仍然是我最好的工具！
(ALL ROARING)
(GUNFIRE)
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
This place is like a beacon.
这地方跟一个灯塔似的
It's Kate Lethbridge-Stewart, isn't it?
这是凯特fixme, 对吗？
- But...
- Sarah-Jane Smith. Hello.
- 但是...  - 我是莎拉-简·史密斯, 你好
Your father said it
might be a family affair.
你父亲说这可能是一个家庭事务
- So, show me where to find him.
- All right.
- 所以, 告诉我哪里可以找到他  - 好吧
- EXPLOSIONS)
{GUNFIRE)
(ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
(LIGHTNING CRASHING)
Distract them, Brigadier.
引开他们, 准将
This is my fault. If I can shut down
the mainframe...
这是我的错, 如果我能关闭电脑主机...
I'm sure we've met before.
我敢肯定我们之前见过
I doubt it.
我怀疑没有
(PULSATING)
{ROARING)
{GRUNTS)
(DISTORTED) Bring my jailer here.
带我的狱卒过来
Stop her! This time, destroy her.
阻止她！这次, 消灭她
My strength is growing, jailer.
我的力量在增长, 狱卒
Your defences are powerless to stop me.
你的防御太弱, 阻止不了我
I'm amazed at your awesome ingenuity,
我很惊讶于你的手艺
Travers.
The late Professor Travers.
已故的fixme教授
This is my world now.
现在这是我的世界了
Oh, of course.
噢, 当然
I'm doubtless you'll make a better job
of it than we humans have.
毫无疑问你会比我们人类干得好
Sarah, take this. It's for my father.
莎拉, 拿着这个, 这是给我父亲的
I'm a rotten shot. You hang onto it.
我枪法很烂, 你留着吧
Look, I don't want to fight.
I want my dad back.
看, 我并不想参战, 我只要我的爸爸回来
Where's the back-up gone to?
后援都去哪儿了？
(ALL ROARING)
We humans are basically
a gregarious species,
我们人类基本上是群君物种
er, Great One,
despite exceptions, like Daniel Hinton.
尽管有些例外, 比如丹尼尔·辛顿
Deleted from my system.
从我的系统里删掉了
Oh, I see.
噢, 我明白了
So, resistance is obviously...
What's the word?
所以, 抵抗显然是...那个词是什么来着？
Useless? Good.
徒劳的？很好
But tell me, Brigadier.
但是告诉我, 准将
Which part of my Great Plan do you think
is most strategically successful?
我的伟大计划中哪一部分你觉得在战略上是最成功的
- None of it.
- What?
- 全都不是  - 什么？
For a so-called Intelligence,
you're pretty damn stupid.
虽然叫做“大智慧”, 其实你相当蠢
You're still trapped.
你还是被困住了
- No.
- That's not a body.
- 不  - 那不是fixme
You've trapped yourself
in a web of silicon and cables.
你把自己困在了硅晶和线缆的网里
All of it stolen.
And you can't venture beyond it.
I have slammed the door on my darkness.
我已经关上了黑暗的门
And I shall perpetuate myself in every machine
and every being in my world.
我将长存于我世界中每一台机器, 每一个生命里面
Balderdash.
胡言乱语
Your power goes no further than
the mainframe of this campus.
你的能力跑不出这个园区里面的主机
All anyone has to do is to pull the plug.
任何人只要拔下插头就可以了
(MOUTHING)
Stay out of sight till I'm back.
躲起来直到我回来为止
No, Sarah. - Please.
不, 莎拉 - 别
Protect the generators.
保护发电机
I shall burrow deep into the Earth's roots
and reach high into its skies.
我将下潜入入树根, 上飞于天空
And the humans shall provide me
with new machines
而且人类会为同提供新的机器
and new bodies.
和新的身体
Dad!
爸爸！
Kate.
凯特
COMPUTER: (REPEATING) Access denied.
拒绝访问
(WHIZZING)
Access denied, Victoria, my dear.
访问被拒了, 维多利亚, 我亲爱的
It's not too late.
还不算太迟
Way, way out of time.
太, 太迟了
Let's see what the
New World has in store.
让我们看看新世界有什么fixme
- Get away from her!
-(GUNSHOT)
离她远点！
Turn off the power!
关闭电源！
That's what I'm trying to do!
我正要干这个！
(GUNSHOT)
I'm sorry, Dad.
对不起, 爸爸
As bad as your mother.
跟你母亲一样差fixme
Oh, you have blood ties.
噢, 你们有血缘纽带
Very well. I need more Yetis.
很好, 我还需要些雪怪
She can be the next.
她可以是下一个
- ROARING)
{GUNSHOT)
Ah!
啊！
Daniel?
丹尼尔？
(GROWLING)
Daniel.
丹尼尔
I know you're still clinging there.
我知道你还在那里
(ROARING)
Daniel, remember your disciplines.
丹尼尔, 记住你的纪律
Daniel, fight the evil.
丹尼尔, 同邪恶斗争
Remember your inner strength.
记住你的内在力量
Remember the sword
that cuts through the thorns of deceit.
记住那把剑, 斩断欺骗的荆棘
Be that sword, Daniel!
成为那把剑吧, 丹尼尔
Remember!
记住！
-(ROARING)
-(LAUGHING)
(SPHERE BEEPING)
(GUNSHOTS)
- Daniel?
-(LAUGHING)
丹尼尔？
You're dead.
你死了
(SCREAMING)
No, Daniel! Destroy the generators!
不, 丹尼尔！摧毁发电机！
I am not defeated!
我没被打败！
Leave our world alone!
离开我们的世界！
It's my world!
这是我的世界！
Go back to Hell, you're not wanted here.
回到地狱去吧, 这里不欢迎你
(GROANING AND WHIMPERING)
(ENERGY PULSATING)
(PULSATING)
Dad.
爸爸
It's all right, Kate. It's gone.
没事了, 凯特, 它消失了
This time, it's gone for good.
这一次, 它永远离开了
Brigadier! Brigadier!
准将！准将！
Miss Smith. I knew
there was someone here I could rely on.
史密斯小姐, 我就知道至少还是一个可以信赖的人
- Oh, have you two, er...
- Yes. We've met.
- 噢, 你们俩是不是...  - 是的, 我们见过
It's just like old times, eh?
就跟以前一样, 嗯？
And I still don't know what's going on.
(LAUGHING)
我还是不知道发生了什么？
Well, someone else can clear up. Let's just go home.
嗯，会有人来收拾的。我们还是回家吧
So, he said it was Victoria's dress.
这么说, 他说过是维多利亚的裙子
fixme
And I said, "Well, as long as
Albert didn't wear it."”
然后我说：“哦, 只要阿尔伯特没有穿过”
And you think it could have been her.
你以为这可能是她fixme
1 don't know. There's no trace of her.
She just vanished into thin air.
我不知道, 没有她的踪迹。她消失在空气中了
Certain people we know
make a habit of that.
fixme
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Do you know, companions used to be
something only dowager aunts had.
No, Sarah, it applies to families as well.
Oh, yes, families.
Dad, this is Gordon.
Gordy, say hello to granddad.
爸爸, 这是戈登。戈迪, 跟外公说你好
Hello, Gordy.
你好, 戈迪
You're not shy, are you?
你不害羞, 是吧？
I've got another friend too.
我也另外有个朋友
Oh? What's his name?
噢, 他叫什么名字？
Danny. But only I can see him.
丹尼, 但只有我能看见他
Oh.
噢
哦
Well, you'd better tell me all about him.
那, 你最好把他的事都告诉我
I'm ravenous. Fancy a pizza?
我饿死了, 对披萨有兴趣吗？
You know, I think I'd rather have a pint.
知道不, 我想我还是来一品脱
Make it a cup of tea, and you're on.
跑一杯茶, 你就fixme
(BOTH LAUGHING)
献给Douglas Camfield和Gerald Blake
（前者是《Daleks大计划》《恐惧之网》《Zygons的恐怖》等集的导演，1984年去世；
后者是《可恶的雪人》《时间入侵》等集的导演，1991年去世）
中文翻译: 巴蛮子sz @ 新浪微博